Guide to the Terry Tempest Williams Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Terry Tempest Williams papers
1872-2015
1967-2015
WA MSS S-2700
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
350.71
(459 boxes) + 12 broadsides
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, including manuscripts and proofs, journals, notebooks, day books, research files, photographs, printed materials, awards, artwork, and audiovisual materials related to the life and work of Terry Tempest Williams.
Williams, Terry Tempest, 1955-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2011.
March 2013 Acquisition: gift of Terry Tempest Williams, 2013.
Custodial History
Materials in Series I. Papers Prior to 2002 were previously on deposit at the J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 153-154, 156, 357-359, 362: Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 360-361: Restricted until January 1, 2037. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 161-162, 354-356 (audiovisual materials): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Terry Tempest Williams
Terry Tempest Williams is an American writer, poet, naturalist, and environmental and social activist. Her writings link environmental causes with social justice and women's health, art, politics, and spirituality.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, including manuscripts and proofs, journals, notebooks, day books, research files, photographs, printed materials, awards, artwork, and audiovisual materials related to the life and work of Terry Tempest Williams.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: Series I. Papers Prior to 2002; Series II. Papers Chiefly After 2002; and March 2013 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; American literature -- 21st century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Authors, American -- 21st century -- Archives; Environmentalism -- United States; Natural history -- United States; Women authors; Photographs; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Williams, Terry Tempest, 1955-
- Papers prior to 2002, 1872-2002 bulk: 1967-2002; Series I
  Custodial History
  These materials were previously on deposit at the J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah.
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1967-1975 (Box 1)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1980-1982 (Box 6a)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1982-1983 (Box 6b)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1984-1985 (Box 6c)
  - Journals and Great Salt Lake Notebooks, 1986-1989 (Box 6)
  - TTW (Terry Tempest Williams) Family, 1987-1993 (Box 7a)
  - TTW (Terry Tempest Williams) Family, 1987-1993 (Box 7b)
  - Award and notebooks (Box 8a)
  - Correspondence, Individuals (Box 8b)
  - Correspondence, Individuals (Box 9)
  - Publishers (Box 10)
  - Brandt & Brandt; Projects; Invitations and Requests; Universities (Box 11)
  - Brandt & Brandt; Projects; Invitations and Requests; Universities (Box 12)
  - General Mail including Fan Mail (Box 13)
  - General Mail including Fan Mail (Box 14)
  - General Mail including Fan Mail (Box 15)
  - General Mail including Fan Mail (Box 16)
  - General Mail including Fan Mail (Box 17)
  - Correspondence regarding Refuge (Box 18)
  - Essays, Deseret News columns, reviews by TTW, research, notes (Box 19)
  - Essays, Deseret News columns, reviews by TTW, research, notes (Box 20)
  - Essays, Deseret News columns, reviews by TTW, research, notes (Box 21)
  - Essays, Deseret News columns, reviews by TTW, research, notes (Box 22)
  - Essays, Deseret News columns, reviews by TTW, research, notes (Box 23)
  - Books by TTW
    - Secret Language of Snow, 2 (Box 24)
    - Pieces of White Shell, 1989; 2 (Box 24)
    - Edges: The Marsh (Box 24)
    - Between Cattails, 1984; 3 (Box 24)
    - Earthly Messengers, 2 (Box 24)
    - "In Cahoots with Coyote", 3 (Box 24)
    - Coyote's Canyon, 6 (Box 24)
  - Research and Notes (Box 25)
  - Research and Notes (Box 26)
  - Research and Notes (Box 27)
  - Refuge (Box 28)
  - Refuge (Box 29)
  - Refuge (Box 30)
  - Refuge (Box 31)
  - Refuge (Box 32)
  - Refuge (Box 33)
  - Refuge (Box 34)
  - Refuge (Box 35)
  - Refuge (Box 36)
  - Refuge (Box 37)
  - Refuge (Box 38)
  - Refuge (Box 39)
  - Refuge (Box 40)
  - Refuge (Box 41)
  - Refuge (Box 42)
  - Refuge (Box 43)
  - Refuge (Box 44a)
  - Refuge (Box 44b)
  - Reviews (Box 45)
  - Museum of Natural History, Nuclear Testing (Box 46)
  - The Wilderness Society, Correspondence and Publications (Box 47)
  - Other Environmental Organizations (Box 48)
  - Projects including Project 2000 (Box 49)
  - Projects including Project 2000 (Box 50)
  - The Dinner Party, Friends and writers working in environmental fields met for a dinner party (Box 51)
  - Conferences, workshops and course work (Box 52)
  - Conferences, workshops and course work (Box 53)
  - Books, book tour schedules; Audio press: "A Desert Sea" (KUED) (Box 54)
  - News Clippings, Journals, other Publications (Box 55)
  - News Clippings, Journals, other Publications (Box 56)
  - News Clippings, Journals, other Publications (Box 57)
  - News Clippings, Journals, other Publications (Box 58)
  - News Clippings, Journals, other Publications (Box 59)
  - Scrapbooks, 1973 (Box 60 (Oversize))
  - Refuge scrapbook album, 1991 (Box 61a (Oversize))
  - Refuge - Reviews and clippings, 1990s (Box 61b (Oversize))
  - Women in Communications, Inc. - Utah Chapter, award, 1993 (Box 61b (Oversize))
  - Terry My Toad, scrapbook, 1984 (Box 62a (Oversize))
  - Northern Lights newspapers, 1991-1992 (Box 62b (Oversize))
    Scope and Contents
    Also contains two other publications: NEO. (1988) and Ancient Forests on the Olympic National Forest (1990).
  - Border Regional Library Association award, 1985-1992 (Box 63a (Oversize))
    Includes an issue of American Way Magazine (November 1992), Utah Museum of Natural History correspondence and a McCall's Magazine typescript.
  - Nature art prints, matted (Box 63a (Oversize))
  - The Darkest Sun, newspaper, 1991 (Box 63a (Oversize))
  - Family photograph album (Box 63b (Oversize))
  - Various oversize materials, 1985-1991 (Box 64 (Oversize))
  - Correspondence and Manuscripts, 1989-1994
    - Day Planners, 1994 (Box 65)
    - Requests (Box 65)
    - Brandt and Brandt correspondence (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1989 (Box 65)
    - Friends, miscellaneous correspondence (Box 65)
    - Correspondence, 1994; 5 (Box 65)
    - Utah correspondence (Box 65)
    - Lyn Dalebout (Box 65)
    - Alice Gabriner, US News and World Report, 1994 (Box 65)
    - David M. Johns, paper, correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 65)
    - Robin Kamerling, Letter re. Refuge (Box 65)
    - Barry Lopez (Box 65)
    - Sandra Lopez (Box 65)
    - Ton Lyon, re. Logan Canyon, 1994 (Box 65)
    - William Mulder, re. Centennial Book, 1994 (Box 65)
    - Doug Peacock, copies of letters, 1994 (Box 65)
    - Karen Shepherd (Box 65)
    - Charles Wilkinson, letter, short story (Box 65)
    - Repertory Dance Theater, 1994 (Box 65)
    - TIW editorial, National Parks article, Salt Lake Tribune, 1993 (Box 65)
    - TTW essay, Nature Conservancy Anthology, Pantheon Books, 1994 (Box 65)
    - TTW, "Throwing Flowers at Evil", 1994 (Box 65)
    - "Wilderness Echos," review of "An Unspoken Hunger" (Box 65)
    - "The Erotic Landscape," submitted to Harper's Magazine (Box 65)
    - Drafts: letter to Mary Frank, Time Zero (Box 65)
    - "What Are We Afraid Of?," notes TTW (Box 65)
    - TTW, "What We Forget" (Box 65)
    - "The Erotic Landscape," TTW, Harper's Bazaar, killed, too controversial, 1994 (Box 65)
    - TTW, "Making Vows" (Box 65)
    - TTW, "Who is this Masked Duck, Anyway?" (Box 65)
    - TTW, "The Wild Card," draft (Box 65)
  - Correspondence, Manuscripts, Conferences, Talks, Environment, 1988-1994
    - Personal, Miscellaneous (Box 66)
    - Awards, 1988 (Box 66)
    - Excerpt from Colorado Daily, 1998 (Box 66)
    - Northword Audio Press, agreement, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous publishers, broadcasts (Box 66)
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., Prentice Hall, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Laura Sims (Box 66)
    - Mary Jane Simmons, Phillips Gallery, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Renee Wayne Golden, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Photo, football, red rocks (Box 66)
    - Leadership Techniques for Women, three reaction papers, 1994 (Box 66)
    - TTW, "Subcultures of the West: The Value of Regional Diversity", 1988 (Box 66)
    - TTW, "Water Songs" (Box 66)
    - Notes, thoughts, maps (Box 66)
    - Indiana Talk, 1993 (Box 66)
    - Manuscript notes, thoughts, 1991 (Box 66)
    - Port Townsend, 1992 (Box 66)
    - Talk, 1992 (Box 66)
    - Portland talk (Box 66)
    - Allegiances, Notes, thoughts (Box 66)
    - Friends of Great Salt Lake (Box 66)
    - Snake River Institute, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance (SUWA) (Box 66)
    - The Wilderness Society (Box 66)
    - Wild Earth (Box 66)
    - Wild Forest Review: Portland, Oregon (Box 66)
    - "Oh Beautiful Girl!" Shining Girl! TTW and Debra Fraiser (Box 66)
    - Conference Information (Box 66)
    - Noetic Sciences Conference, talk, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Society of Environmental Journalists, Sundance, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Schedule for Boise visit, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Wilderness Conference, Santa Fe, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Conference, in the Thoreau Tradition, III, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Western Literature Association Conference, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Stegner Lecture, draft, 1993 (Box 66)
    - Hospice Talk, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Vassar College Lecture, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Summer Anthology (SOMOS), )1994 (Box 66)
    - Rotary meeting responses, 1994 (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous conference information (Box 66)
    - League of Conservation Voters (Box 66)
    - The Stranger, TTW article (Box 66)
    - Wildlife Damage Review (Box 66)
  - Correspondence; general, personal, business, 1991-1995
    - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, comments on specific events (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, 1994; 4 (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, friends, 2 (Box 67)
    - Brandt and Brandt (Box 67)
    - Communion, Anchor/Doubleday, David Rosenberg (Box 67)
    - Northland Publishing, Kathryn Wilder, 1994 (Box 67)
    - Pantheon Books (Box 67)
    - Publishers (Box 67)
    - Requests/Invitations, 5 (Box 67)
    - Notes for TTW assistant re. correspondence (Box 67)
    - Messages from assistant (Box 67)
    - Edward G. Lueders (Box 67)
    - Stephen Lyons (Box 67)
    - Margaret "Peg" Millett (Box 67)
    - Dave Petersen (Box 67)
    - Keith Petersen (Box 67)
    - John Schow (Box 67)
    - Rick Springer (Box 67)
  - Conferences, Publications, Manuscripts, 1988-1994
    - Brooke Williams, article (Box 68)
    - Guggenheim applicants (Box 68)
    - Lannan Foundation Literary Award, Fellowship (Box 68)
    - Speakers Bureau (Box 68)
    - Conferences and Symposiums (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, retreats (Box 68)
    - Bread Loaf Writers' Conference, 1994 (Box 68)
    - Sundance, talk (Box 68)
    - Wallace Stegner Lecture Series, correspondence (Box 68)
    - Talking leaves Journal, Jesse Wolf Hardin (Box 68)
    - High Country News, Ed Marston (Box 68)
    - Sierra, Annie Stine (Box 68)
    - Women's Sports and Fitness Magazine, 1994 (Box 68)
    - UTNE Reader Visionfest (Box 68)
    - Wild Earth, Marcia Cary (Box 68)
    - Antelope Island Visitor's Center (Box 68)
    - Bolsa Chica Land Trust (Box 68)
    - Nature Conservancy (Box 68)
    - Repertory Dance Theater (RDT) Linda Smith (Box 68)
    - Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance (SUWA) (Box 68)
    - Utah Museum of Natural History (Box 68)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, May Castleberry (Box 68)
    - The Wildlands Project (Box 68)
    - Wildlife Damage Review (WDR) (Box 68)
    - The Wilderness Society (Box 68)
    - Yolo Audubon Society, 1992-1994 (Box 68)
    - Sermons by the Rev. James L. Fredrick, 1988-1994 (Box 68)
    - Jesse Wolf Hardin (Box 68)
    - Paper on Refuge, Karla Armbruster (Box 68)
    - Paper on Refuge, Suzanna Ross (Box 68)
    - "Sustainability," draft, TTW; list of books (Box 68)
    - TTW notes: "A Note about this Collaboration" (Box 68)
    - Elements of Love, II. Fire, TTW (Box 68)
    - Testimony, TTW notes (Box 68)
    - Earth Day, draft, TTW, 1995 (Box 68)
    - Cover for "A Great and Peculiar Beauty" (Box 68)
    - Notes, Research, TTW, 2 (Box 68)
    - Review, An Unspoken Hunger (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous writings, pages, notes, 2 (Box 68)
    - Stephen Trimble, Epilogue: Remembering Edward Abbey (Box 68)
    - Sally Brock, poetry (Box 68)
    - Lorelei Kellogg, miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 68)
    - Maria Stafford, two stories, note (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets, releases (Box 68)
  - Correspondence, TTW Manuscripts drafts, 1983-1988
    - Photocopies of photographs that were transferred (Box 69)
    - Letter from Wallace Stegner, 1983 (Box 69)
    - Correspondence: Eliot Porter, Mark Klett, Doug Peacock, Pinar (Box 69)
    - Correspondence: Barry and Sandra Lopez (Box 69)
    - Correspondence: publishers, 1987 (Box 69)
    - Cloth bound notebook (Box 69)
    - TTW, "Local Color-The Lives and Land of Southern Utah" (Box 69)
    - TTW, "Land of Frozen Rainbows" (Box 69)
    - TTW manuscript, "Between Cattails" (Box 69)
    - TTW draft, Kate's Necklace (Box 69)
    - TTW draft, The Bird Letters of Evelyn Bliss (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts, Lizard Woman, 2 (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts; "Just Crows" and "Manus Peak" (Box 69)
    - TTW draft, A Woman's Fire (Box 69)
    - TTW draft, William H. Beale (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts, SUWA Talk (Southern Utah Wilderness Association) (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts, Navajo research, notes (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts, Annui (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts, "In the Country of Grasses" (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts: "Curator," "Unknown Utah," "Utah Holiday" (Box 69)
    - TTW drafts, Earthley Messengers, 1988 (Box 69)
  - TTW Manuscripts, 1984-1988
    - "A Potshard and Some Corn Pollen" (Box 70)
    - "The Infinite Order of Kingbirds" (Box 70)
    - Research, correspondence re. Pieces of White Shell (Box 70)
    - Pieces of White Shell, manuscript, note from Laurie Schieffelin (Box 70)
    - Pieces of White Shell, manuscript, 1984; 4 (Box 70)
    - Galleys - Pieces of White Shell, 1984 (Box 70)
    - Coyote's Canyon, drafts, 1988; 4 (Box 70)
    - Refuge, draft (Box 70)
  - Personal, Correspondence, Museum of Natural History, Manuscripts, 1983-1992
    - Personal (Box 71)
    - Talk on Birds (Box 71)
    - On starting a Green Party (Box 71)
    - Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Requests and Invitations (Box 71)
    - Utah Conservation Groups/others - mailing lists (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - Friends (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - Carl Brandt (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - Patrick Cone (Box 71)
    - Jackson David Trading Co. (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - Tom Lyon (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - David Petersen (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - Karen Shepherd (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - Ann Zwinger (Box 71)
    - Correspondence - University of Utah (Box 71)
    - Correspondence, 1992 February 17 (Box 71)
    - Student Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Words and Photographs by Stephen Trimble (Box 71)
    - Poems by John Marrs, 1989 (Box 71)
    - Utah Museum of Natural History, 4 (Box 71)
    - American Museum of Natural History, 1983 (Box 71)
    - Montezuma Creek Elementary School (Box 71)
    - Manuscripts, notes (Box 71)
    - "Just Crows" (Box 71)
    - "Who is this Masked Duck, Anyway?" - TTW (Box 71)
    - Notes - "The Sacrifice Flower," "Navajo Folk Tales" (Box 71)
    - University of Utah Press Agreement - "The Storytellers", 1984 (Box 71)
    - "The Storytellers" (Box 71)
    - From A Naturalist's Notebook - TTW (Box 71)
  - Correspondence, Manuscripts volume 1-3: Day Planner, 1983-1988
    - Appointment books, 1983-1988 (Box 72)
    - Photos to be copied - placed in Multimedia (Box 72)
    - Business (Box 72)
    - Booksellers - correspondence (Box 72)
    - Publishers (Box 72)
    - Dream Garden Press (Box 72)
    - Agreement - Pieces of White Shell (Box 72)
    - Pieces of White Shell reviews - Ed Lueders and Tery Orme (Box 72)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons (Box 72)
    - Sharon Alderman - weaving (Box 72)
    - The Green Belt Movement - Kenya (Box 72)
    - NGO Forum 85 (Box 72)
    - Article for McCall's Magazine re: Nairobi - Women/relation to national world - TTW (Box 72)
    - Salt Lake Tribune reviews of Eliot Porter and Wallace Stegner, 1984 (Box 72)
    - Riddell Photo Graphics (Box 72)
    - News articles, 1986; 3 (Box 72)
    - Utah Wilderness Calendar with notations by TTW, 1986 (Box 72)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 6 (Box 73)
  - Manuscripts and Research
    - Birdlore (includes notes, research), 4 (Box 74)
    - Birdlore, Utah Birds, course description (Box 74)
    - Mythology of Owls (Box 74)
    - "Pukak" - small envelope of notes (Box 74)
    - "Just Crows" (Box 74)
    - Earth Goddesses (Box 74)
    - Copies of sketches for Pieces of White Shell by C. Brycelea (Box 74)
    - Pieces of White Shell - miscellany (Box 74)
    - Pieces of White Shell - Notes by Deb (Box 74)
    - Pieces of White Shell - student papers (Box 74)
    - Storytelling article - Salt Lake Tribune, 1983 May 13 (Box 74)
    - "There Are Lessons Along the Way" - TTW (Box 74)
    - Between Cattails - TTW (Box 74)
    - Sketches for The Secret Language of Snow (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous material for The Secret Language of Snow (Box 74)
    - "Forward" - TTW (Box 74)
    - "Local Color - The Lives and Land of Southern Utah" - TTW (Box 74)
    - "Bringing Nature Inside" - TTW (Box 74)
    - "A Naturalist's Notebook" - TTW (Box 74)
    - "Edges" - mss TTW, note from J. Dewey (Box 74)
    - "The Canyon's Edge" - script TTW, 3 (Box 74)
    - "An Interview with Kokopelli" - TTW (Box 74)
    - Notebooks, 3 (Box 74)
    - Nature watching - typed notes (Box 74)
    - "A Tribute to Grandma and Grandpa" - TTW (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous manuscript pages (Box 74)
  - Correspondence, News Articles, 1981-1989
    - Curriculum Vitae - TTW (Box 75)
    - Edward Abbey Memorial - notes (Box 75)
    - Correspondence - Carl Brandt (Box 75)
    - Correspondence- Publishers (Little Brown, Scribner's, Sierra Club, Knopf, and Pantheon) (Box 75)
    - Correspondence - Publishers (Gibbs Smith, University of Utah Press) (Box 75)
    - Dan Frank - Viking (Box 75)
    - Correspondence - Publishers (file from TTW), 1987 (Box 75)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 75)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 75)
    - Correspondence - Friends (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous - correspondence (Box 75)
    - Children's letters, 1981-1988 (Box 75)
    - Correspondence - Jennifer Dewey (Box 75)
    - Doug Peacock (Box 75)
    - Letter re. Charles Wilkinson (Box 75)
    - Cards for Talk or class / notes to Laura Simms (Box 75)
    - Lynne Tempest, "Indian Women and Their Working Relationship with the Earth:, 1981 (Box 75)
    - News clippings - TTW at Marriott program; death of Kathryn B. Tempest, 1989 (Box 75)
    - New Articles, 2 (Box 75)
  - University of Utah, Museum of Natural History, Green Belt Movement in Kenya, Conferences, 1983-1992
    - "Integral Vistas" (Box 76)
    - Museum of Natural History (Box 76)
    - Letters to Museum Family by TTW, 1983 (Box 76)
    - Museum Program Brochures (Box 76)
    - Marriott Reserve (Box 76)
    - University of Utah miscellany - includes course schedules (Box 76)
    - Natural History writers - University of Utah, 1988 (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous notes, messages (Box 76)
    - Reviews (Box 76)
    - Green Belt Movement in Kenya (Box 76)
    - Orion - letter, Tenth Anniversary Issue, 1992 (Box 76)
    - Selected Poems for Terry Tempest Williams by Geraldine R. Pratt (Box 76)
    - John Schow - Poems (Box 76)
    - National Wildlife Federation Conservation Summit, 1984 (Box 76)
    - Conferences (Box 76)
    - "In the Thoreau Tradition," - Conference, Missoula, Montana, 1990 (Box 76)
  - Thesis, Pieces of White Shell, "Edges" and other manuscript drafts, correspondence with artists, notes
    - Thesis notes, 3 (Box 77)
    - Pieces of White Shell - permissions (Box 77)
    - Clifford Brycelea - illustrations, correspondence (Box 77)
    - Pieces of White Shell - notes, drafts, 2 (Box 77)
    - Pieces of White Shell - manuscript, notes (Box 77)
    - Pieces of White Shell - publicity, 1984 (Box 77)
    - Responses to Pieces of White Shell (Box 77)
    - "Edges" - correspondence: Little, Brown, Jennifer Dewey (Box 77)
    - Jennifer Dewey - illustrations, correspondence (Box 77)
    - "Edges" - manuscript drafts (Box 77)
    - "Edges: The Marsh" - some correspondence, some research and notes (Box 77)
    - "Edges: The Marsh" manuscripts (Box 77)
    - "Edges: The Marsh" with notations (Box 77)
    - "Edges" - children's letters (Box 77)
    - "Edges: the Sea," notes, manuscript draft (Box 77)
  - Writings
    - Snow activities (Box 78)
    - "Snow Language" - first draft, 1980 (Box 78)
    - "Snow Language" - bibliography draft, 1982 (Box 78)
    - "Snow Language" - TTW and Ted Major (Box 78)
    - "Snow Language" - early drafts, 2 (Box 78)
    - "Snow Language" - TTW and Ted Major (Box 78)
    - "Snow Language" - typed copy (Box 78)
    - The Secret Language of Snow - Sierra Club publishers, correspondence, manuscript drafts, 1980-1983; 3 (Box 78)
    - "After the Tongan Feast" - TTW (Box 78)
    - "Lizard Woman" - manuscript drafts (Box 78)
    - "An Emergence" - TTW (Box 78)
    - The Urban Naturalist (Box 78)
  - Conferences, Correspondence, Courses, 1932-1986
    - Conferences (Box 79)
    - Patterns of Change: Alternative Futures Conference, 1980 (Box 79)
    - Comments on TTW discussion of the Women's Conference in Nairobi, Kenya, 1985 (Box 79)
    - Parks in the West Conference (Box 79)
    - Canyonlands Field Institute - description / projected goals and budget, circa 1986 (Box 79)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 79)
    - Correspondence - Carl Brandt (Box 79)
    - Correspondence - Scribner's (Box 79)
    - American Players Theatre (Box 79)
    - Outside Magazine - slides, descriptive mailer, John Telford portfolio (Box 79)
    - Utah Holiday - P. Swenson comments on TTW review of The Color Purple (Box 79)
    - Dream Garden Press (Box 79)
    - The River Why - review by TTW, 1983 (Box 79)
    - Utah Wetlands (Box 79)
    - Information on Birds for course taught by TTW (Box 79)
    - Utah Birds - lectures (Box 79)
    - Navajo/Navaho article (Box 79)
    - "Classroom Change and Scientific Literacy: A Case Study" - Richard Butt, 1981 (Box 79)
    - "Dare the School Build a New Social Order?" - George S. Counts, 1932 (Box 79)
    - Science in Elementary Schools, taught by TTW, University of Utah, 1981 (Box 79)
    - Letters from Montezuma Creek (Box 79)
    - Beads: Ribbons, Montezuma Creek (Box 79)
    - Lectures, Education 512, Winter, 1981 (Box 79)
    - Intro Utah Birds, course taught by TTW, University of Utah, 1982 (Box 79)
    - The Romance of Winter, Leisure Studies 194R - course taught by TTW and Brooke Williams, 1982; 2 (Box 79)
    - Guide for Non-sexist Language (Box 79)
  - Native Americans, Storytelling, other, 1981-1982
    - Articles by Brooke Williams (Box 80)
    - "An Ancient Roof" - notes (Box 80)
    - The Advocate - Joel Taxel, 1982 (Box 80)